<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title type="text" xml:lang="en">Another Blog Blog</title>
  <link type="application/atom+xml" href="feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link type="text/html" href="http://www.anotherblogblog.co.uk" rel="alternate"/>
  <updated>2017-08-23T23:25:44+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.anotherblogblog.co.uk</id>
  <author>
    <name>Mr. Brompton</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright Mr.Brompton 2017</rights>

  
  <entry>
    <title>Privacy</title>
    <link href="http://www.anotherblogblog.co.uk /politics/2017/08/23/privacy/"/>
    <updated>2017-08-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.anotherblogblog.co.uk/politics/2017/08/23/privacy</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;iframe id=&quot;ad&quot; style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-eu.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;amp;OneJS=1&amp;amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;amp;MarketPlace=GB&amp;amp;source=ac&amp;amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;amp;tracking_id=mrbrompton-21&amp;amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;amp;region=GB&amp;amp;placement=1478945567&amp;amp;asins=1478945567&amp;amp;linkId=dd0103f222a88b95d2cfddcca5c5510f&amp;amp;show_border=false&amp;amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true&amp;amp;price_color=333333&amp;amp;title_color=ff6600&amp;amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;online-privacy-and-you&quot;&gt;Online Privacy and YOU!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mr-brompton&quot;&gt;Mr. Brompton&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;fb-like&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ABB.Mr.Brompton&quot; data-layout=&quot;button_count&quot; data-action=&quot;like&quot; data-size=&quot;large&quot; data-show-faces=&quot;false&quot; data-share=&quot;false&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fb-follow&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ABB.Mr.Brompton&quot; data-layout=&quot;button_count&quot; data-size=&quot;large&quot; data-show-faces=&quot;false&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I remember a happy childhood, often in response to my outrageous style or strong political views I cited the common phrase ‘It’s a free country’, under the notion that if I hadn’t committed a crime, I was a free person with no reason to assume I was under surveillance or investigation. This has all changed. Here in the UK, we now live in the most watched state in the world. Under the guise of security theatre, the threat of terrorism has meant we have given unprecedented access of our lives to the Government, and in the same breathe everyone else who has an internet connection. So what’s the problem? I have nothing to hide so why should I be concerned?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/1984.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1984 extract&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-problems-with-ipa&quot;&gt;The problems with IPA:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only was the &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.co.uk/tech-policy/2016/11/investigatory-powers-act-privacy-disaster-waiting-to-happen/&quot;&gt;IPA pushed through without proper parliamentary debate&lt;/a&gt;, It was done so using extremely dirty tactics meaning the act was enforceable before any serious opposition could be brought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even before the act many innocent people were being watched despite no previous criminal offences, links to criminal organisations or a background of any criminal activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;quot&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;The most extreme surveilance in the history of western democracy&amp;quot;&lt;span class=&quot;ref&quot;&gt;- Edward Snowden&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the tenure of the acts predecessor, Regulation of Investigatory Powers Act 2000 (RIPA),  while investigating the pleb-gate scandal &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/media/media-blog/2014/sep/08/regulation-investigatory-powers-act-snoopers-charter&quot;&gt;The Police accessed the records of Newton Dunn&lt;/a&gt; in order to ascertain the identity of the ‘anonymous source’ who had revealed the information. This was then used to punish the whistle-blowers concerned. This type of action will make it extremely difficult for anyone suspecting foul-play to report it anonymously. It doesn’t stop there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/dec/25/british-councils-used-investigatory-powers-ripa-to-secretly-spy-on-public&quot;&gt;Midlothian council used the act to spy on people feeding pidgeons&lt;/a&gt;,   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/dec/25/british-councils-used-investigatory-powers-ripa-to-secretly-spy-on-public&quot;&gt;Lancaster city council spied on dog walkers&lt;/a&gt;, there are endless lists of minor infractions being used as reason to survail large groups of innocent people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the above cases were covered by RIPA and as such required the permission of the courts to enact, the new bill however bypasses such controls and puts your information, phone calls, text messages and the rest of it directly into the hands of the department concerned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-the-risks&quot;&gt;What are the risks?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if I have nothing to hide I shouldn’t be concerned? If that is the argument against mass surveillance it can be blown out of the water with these simple stories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cindy B is a social worker from Canada, with no criminal record, or even a parking ticket to her name. She raised issues about funding to the Canadian Government, after which she became paranoid that she was being watched and so she submitted a request to view the information about her that the Canadian Government held. The results were surprising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;quot&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;I filed for any documents the department would have about me, and a year and a half later, that DVD arrives in the mail and I thought it’d be a quick view, and I saw one document after another document. Email exchanges, copies of my emails. There was pictures off of my Facebook page. They had screenshots, but they were also following my personal movements. Not only was there copies of different types of talks I was at. There was notes of a talk I did in the middle of the desert of Australia and they weren’t just following me. They were following other people in my circle.&amp;quot;&lt;span class=&quot;ref&quot;&gt;- Cindy B&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-can-this-information-be-miss-used&quot;&gt;How can this information be miss-used?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is another story,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cassidy Wolf was Miss Teen USA. Her browser had a defect in it and that defect allowed someone who had installed what’s called drive by malware on a website and this guy, he got indecent nude images of Cassidy, who was a minor child at the time, he said, “I now have your social media passwords and I have these pictures of you naked, standing in front of your computer, when you were getting dressed in the morning. I’m going to dump them all onto your social media unless you perform live sex acts on camera,”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This hacker was eventually caught after inflicting similar experiences on hundreds of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://irlpodcast.org/episode5/?utm_source=email&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=irl&amp;amp;utm_content=iot-survey&quot;&gt;stories from IRL by Mozilla&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might think ‘That could never happen’ or ‘It won’t happen to me’, you may trust the people responsible for securing the data to keep it safe but the nature of the internet is, once it’s online it’s never going away. The best way to stay safe is to ensure the data doesn’t exist in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the main problem with this the IPA, it makes the data available not only to those who might need it to fight crime, but to those who can, and will use it against you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-happens-when-the-government-or-large-cooperations-decide-they-are-against-you&quot;&gt;What happens when the Government, or large cooperations decide THEY are against you?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the Dakota access pipeline protests, energy transfer partners - The company behind the pipeline hired a private surveillance company to watch the protesters. Although it can’t be proven that anything happened with this information, often the pipelines defence was one step ahead of the protesters and used extreme tactics to attempt to disperse them. With Large US corporations beginning to frack our gorgeous country and laying their oily hands on our NHS what makes us think they won’t use similar tactics against protesters here in the UK?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;does-this-type-of-surveillance-work&quot;&gt;Does this type of surveillance work?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sad truth is, not only does this type of surveillance not work it is actually counter productive. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newscientist.com/article/dn26801-mass-surveillance-not-effective-for-finding-terrorists/&quot;&gt;New Scientist has reported that Surveillance of the entire population, the vast majority of whom are innocent, leads to the diversion of limited intelligence resources in pursuit of huge numbers of false leads. Terrorists are comparatively rare, so finding one is a needle in a haystack problem&lt;/a&gt;. While &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.counterpunch.org/2006/05/24/why-does-the-nsa-engage-in-mass-surveillance-of-americans-when-it-s-statistically-impossible-for-such-spying-to-detect-terrorists/&quot;&gt;Floyd Rudmin goes a step further and shows us the maths behind the problem&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does the IPA still make you feel safer? For me, it certainly does not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;who-can-access-our-data&quot;&gt;Who can access our data?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a huge &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.independent.co.uk/life-style/gadgets-and-tech/news/investigatory-powers-bill-act-snoopers-charter-browsing-history-what-does-it-mean-a7436251.html&quot;&gt;list of authorities legally able to access your browsing history&lt;/a&gt; including the DWP, meaning, if you are unemployed and sign on, your advisor may be able to see exactly how long you watched that cat video for. A darker mind might suggest they could see the exactly how long you were watching porn last night and which videos did it for you.. Although this is a problem in itself, this is just the tip of a very large iceberg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As was stated earlier, the only way to keep the data 100% safe is to ensure it doesn’t exist in the first place, but allowing such a wide number of people access without proper judicial permissions only serves to increase the risk of the information falling into the wrong hands. There are some very smart, dumb people out there who know how to exploit us if they get the right piece of information. Getting hold of it couldn’t be easier and it is only a matter of time before we see this information made available on the dark-web or worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-data-can-be-accessed&quot;&gt;What data can be accessed?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your full browsing history from the last year.
Voice and Video recordings (Thankfully only with a warrant)
NHS and similar Records,
Who you speak to, how long for, when and where.
Your geographic location,
MP’s Communictaons (With permission of the PM)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scary huh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-can-i-do-to-protect-myself&quot;&gt;What can I do to protect myself?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well it’s not all doom and gloom, There are some brilliant ways to negate this problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use a VPN, for example &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B071GDC48J/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1634&amp;amp;creative=6738&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B071GDC48J&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=mrbrompton-21&amp;amp;linkId=510552caee7565a30a5d894240ed7784&quot;&gt;IP Vanish VPN&lt;/a&gt; To hide your personal details and location. This is VITAL is you are using public Wi-Fi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B073XM9JLM/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=mrbrompton-21&amp;amp;camp=1634&amp;amp;creative=6738&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B073XM9JLM&amp;amp;linkId=b342b6ed04df572fa0c4a36895237e04&quot;&gt;Webcam Cover&lt;/a&gt;. Olivia London does it. Facebook’s Mark Zuckerberg does it. So does former FBI director James Comey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use Private Browsing – This will mean your browsing history is not stored locally and no personal data can be accessed from your machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get informed, Listen to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/1478945567/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1634&amp;amp;creative=6738&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1478945567&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=mrbrompton-21&amp;amp;linkId=e841f5c19aef26d67062088a1b61789e&quot;&gt;The Art of Invisibility: The World’s Most Famous Hacker Teaches You How to Be Safe in the Age of Big Brother and Big Data&lt;/a&gt; for free on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Audible-Free-Trial-Digital-Membership/dp/B00OPA2XFG?tag=mrbrompton-21&quot;&gt;Audible with a free 30-day trial&lt;/a&gt;. You can get this book or any other of your choice with no obligation to stay signed up. You even keep the books you buy after you cancel!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;thank-you&quot;&gt;Thank you&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading this post to the end. If this post taught you something, follow us. If you think it could help someone else, share it and if you like what ABB does, visit our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anotherblogblog.co.uk/pages/Support&quot;&gt;contact page&lt;/a&gt; where we are looking for like minded people to work with or our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anotherblogblog.co.uk/pages/contact&quot;&gt;support page&lt;/a&gt; where you can contribute to our survival. Thanks again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fb-like&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ABB.Mr.Brompton&quot; data-layout=&quot;button_count&quot; data-action=&quot;like&quot; data-size=&quot;large&quot; data-show-faces=&quot;false&quot; data-share=&quot;false&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fb-follow&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ABB.Mr.Brompton&quot; data-layout=&quot;button_count&quot; data-size=&quot;large&quot; data-show-faces=&quot;false&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>GE2017: Where next?</title>
    <link href="http://www.anotherblogblog.co.uk /politics/ge2017/2017/08/06/GE2017-where-next/"/>
    <updated>2017-08-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.anotherblogblog.co.uk/politics/ge2017/2017/08/06/GE2017-where-next</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;iframe id=&quot;ad&quot; style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-eu.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;amp;OneJS=1&amp;amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;amp;MarketPlace=GB&amp;amp;source=ac&amp;amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;amp;tracking_id=mrbrompton-21&amp;amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;amp;region=GB&amp;amp;placement=B00KTRZJI2&amp;amp;asins=B00KTRZJI2&amp;amp;linkId=633ddb3082c6f41e1acb44b0d5f78c48&amp;amp;show_border=false&amp;amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true&amp;amp;price_color=333333&amp;amp;title_color=ff6600&amp;amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ge2017-where-next-for-the-uk&quot;&gt;GE2017: Where next for The UK?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is from our previous site build. It will no longer be updated and does not conform to our responsible-reporting policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mr-brompton&quot;&gt;Mr. Brompton&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;fb-like&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ABB.Mr.Brompton&quot; data-layout=&quot;button_count&quot; data-action=&quot;like&quot; data-size=&quot;large&quot; data-show-faces=&quot;false&quot; data-share=&quot;false&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fb-follow&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ABB.Mr.Brompton&quot; data-layout=&quot;button_count&quot; data-size=&quot;large&quot; data-show-faces=&quot;false&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The election is over. The results are in. Theresa May has failed to gain her mandate for a strong and stable leadership and while Labour didn’t win, they grew big time. Since the result of a hung parliament has become clear, Theresa May has been scrambling for more seats to form a majority and with the LibDems still reeling from their last encounter with the blues, there was only ever going to be one choice for the aspiring Prime Minister. The DUP.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/Signpost.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Signpost to the left 2070 to the right 1870&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;who-are-the-dup&quot;&gt;Who are the DUP?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Democratic Unionist Party describe themselves as a party ‘to maintain and enhance Northern Ireland’s constitutional position within the United Kingdom, achieving long-term political stability to deliver a peaceful and prosperous future for our people. ‘ Sounds fair. I may consider writing a full overview of them later on if you’d like to read it comment below - but for now, they are a party with about 10 seats in Parliament and have been reported to be anti-women’s rights, anti gay-rights and deniers of climate change. That said, many of their policies on education and infrastructure are sound and the party leans toward a ‘soft-brexit’ approach. So, not all bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-does-this-mean-for-theresa-may&quot;&gt;What does this mean for Theresa May?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is quite an interesting move from Theresa – although she wasn’t left with much choice. The DUP are the only party willing to enter a deal with enough seats for the Tories to reach the 326 required. The partnership will give Northern Ireland a much stronger position at the negotiating table for BREXIT meaning we may hear the DUP’s views on a hard border more but for me the interesting BREXIT point is that the DUP are a looking for a ‘soft-brexit’, a long way out from May’s war-cry of ‘No deal’. This could mean we may have saved the day in terms of the BREXIT negotiations but then… we all remember how well the LibDems did in Coalition with Cameron when the liberals had 57 seats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-do-the-results-say-about-the-uk-how-is-this-reflected-in-parliament&quot;&gt;What do the results say about the UK? How is this reflected in Parliament?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no denying a massive swing to the left this time around with the first real liberal-left manifesto from any main party in years securing a huge increase for the Labour Party. The question… Does the house of commons now represent the people it leads? Short answer, No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With such a massive surge to the left in both constituency seats and vote share we would expect that our representatives can put up a fair fight – and they can but this doesn’t mean squat next to the coalition now (almost) in power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should explain a little. In British Government both sides can put their ideas on the table. The opposition however, get almost none of these ideas through. Without a majority of 326 it is difficult to persuade enough MP’s to vote in your favour. Often The Government sweeps these ideas under the carpet. (Sometimes to resurface later with the leading parties logo.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is much easier in opposition to persuade a couple Government backbenchers to vote against their own party. This means that the best the left can now hope for is a strong leash tied to the neck of May while hoping NHS privatisation, human rights losses, restriction of freedom of speech, fracking, tax-hikes for the poor, tax cuts for the rich and service cuts will be much more difficult for the PM to push through the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, for now we are fighting a right-wing political agenda as a Conservative coalition with an even further right DUP means we are unable to push forward with progressive policies. I hope you’ve been practicing your parry Mr. Corbyn, you will need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-does-this-mean-for-labour&quot;&gt;What does this mean for Labour?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Labour seem to have passed their crossroads. Just a few months ago a bitter civil war threatened to destroy the party. This election gave a huge mandate to move away from the centre right politics of the previous decades. Labour now have good reason to entrench themselves in the House of Commons using a progressive manifesto the likes of whichKeir Hardie would be proud. All of this with an unknown back-bencher at the helm who beat odds of 1-100 to become party leader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-does-this-mean-for-corbyn&quot;&gt;What does this mean for Corbyn?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a few days into Government and you can bet your last penny that there are ‘anti-Corbyn’ MP’s plotting his demise. With such a strong voter turnout (many of them new voters) it will be difficult to say he is unpopular in the light of his epic defence in Labour’s recent civil war and his valiant fight for number 10. All of this amid one of the dirtiest smear campaigns witnessed in a lifetime, suggesting a weak Corbyn is now impossible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we will have a man who genuinely seems to have a good heart (the unicorn of politicians) at the head of the opposition. With any luck it will remain so for some time to come. We must remember though, that May will not want another election soon, in fact the Labour leader could be a ripe old age of 75 before May chances the polling station again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes things look stark for the future of the progressive left, which is why we must keep fighting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;is-it-all-over&quot;&gt;Is it all over?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another short answer here. No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Blues are weaker, Labour is Stronger but it must remain so if labour have a chance in hell of bending the Government in the right direction. In most elections the mere act of voting is enough, in this one the vote is only the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is still a small glint of hope. Before the ConDem coalition of 2010 we had one other ‘hung parliament’ in living memory (admittedly not my living memory!). In 1974 the Conservative PM Mr. Heath called an election in order to “return a strong government with a firm mandate” to power. Sound familiar? After a hard-fought campaign on both sides, Heath lost his majority and attempted to form a coalition. This coalition didn’t last long and broke down within weeks. This allowed the Labour leader Harold Wilson to form a minority government which did surprisingly well. All of this soon lead to another early election in which Labour’s mandate was secured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is easy to see the parallels here and one would have hoped that PM May would have known all about this story and learned from the past. This wasn’t the case but perhaps Mr. Corbyn can use history to his advantage. Perhaps this time next week… with pressure put into all the right places, Mr. Corbyn can take his rainbow alliance into their rightful place in No. 10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alas, excluding the potential collapse of the coalition Corbyns best hopes of reaching No.10* may have died – unless we can push May for another early election. With this battle almost won, we haven’t yet lost the war. There are other candidates that could push Corbyns agenda once he steps down. John McDonnell is one who comes to mind but in the meantime there are plenty of other ways we can fight the power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;quot&quot;&gt;&quot;Democracy cannot succeed unless those who express their choice are prepared to choose wisely. The real safeguard of democracy, therefore, is education.&quot;&lt;span class=&quot;ref&quot;&gt;-Franklin D. Roosevelt.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-can-now-be-done&quot;&gt;What can now be done?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you voted to Save the NHS, for tax increases for the top 5%, for a crackdown on tax avoidance, for free school meals, for the environment or just because you don’t like May here are a few things you can do to take up the fight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sign this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.change.org/p/winston-theresamay-to-resign-no-to-the-the-democratic-unionist-party-marr-preston-postmanpratt1&quot;&gt;petition against the coalition&lt;/a&gt;(Now closed).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.parliament.uk/get-involved/contact-your-mp/&quot;&gt;Write to your local MP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sign and share &lt;a href=&quot;Petitions&quot;&gt;petitions&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.change.org/&quot;&gt;Change.org&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://home.38degrees.org.uk/&quot;&gt;38 Degrees&lt;/a&gt; are also great places to do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Track and share your &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theyworkforyou.com/mps/&quot;&gt;MP’s Voting Record&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://join.labour.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Join the Labour Party&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_left-wing_political_parties&quot;&gt;other left-wing parties&lt;/a&gt; such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.greenparty.org.uk/&quot;&gt;the Greens&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you enjoyed this content please show your support. It takes many long hours to properly research and write this stuff and real money to publish it. I don’t ask much in return, you could:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like and Share this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like, follow or share &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anotherblogblog.co.uk/&quot;&gt;AnotherBlogBlog on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;fb-like&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ABB.Mr.Brompton&quot; data-layout=&quot;button_count&quot; data-action=&quot;like&quot; data-size=&quot;large&quot; data-show-faces=&quot;false&quot; data-share=&quot;false&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fb-follow&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ABB.Mr.Brompton&quot; data-layout=&quot;button_count&quot; data-size=&quot;large&quot; data-show-faces=&quot;false&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Privatisation Failure</title>
    <link href="http://www.anotherblogblog.co.uk /politics/2017/07/05/Privatisation/"/>
    <updated>2017-07-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.anotherblogblog.co.uk/politics/2017/07/05/Privatisation</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;iframe id=&quot;ad&quot; style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-eu.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;amp;OneJS=1&amp;amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;amp;MarketPlace=GB&amp;amp;source=ac&amp;amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;amp;tracking_id=mrbrompton-21&amp;amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;amp;region=GB&amp;amp;placement=B01F3QQR6Q&amp;amp;asins=B01F3QQR6Q&amp;amp;linkId=6205758dd72bea5bbd2eded281f7484f&amp;amp;show_border=false&amp;amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true&amp;amp;price_color=333333&amp;amp;title_color=ff6600&amp;amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-failure-of-privatisation&quot;&gt;The Failure of Privatisation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mr-brompton&quot;&gt;Mr. Brompton&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;fb-like&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ABB.Mr.Brompton&quot; data-layout=&quot;button_count&quot; data-action=&quot;like&quot; data-size=&quot;large&quot; data-show-faces=&quot;false&quot; data-share=&quot;false&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fb-follow&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ABB.Mr.Brompton&quot; data-layout=&quot;button_count&quot; data-size=&quot;large&quot; data-show-faces=&quot;false&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The NHS crisis is looming over the nation like a dark rain-cloud on an already freezing winters day. Nurses and Doctors are leaving the profession, or even the country in droves, in fact for the first time in history &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.independent.co.uk/news/health/nhs-nurses-leaving-more-joining-up-51-per-cent-four-years-midwives-jeremy-hunt-a7820141.html&quot;&gt;more nurses and midwives are leaving the job than are joining it&lt;/a&gt;. All the while different aspects of the vital service are contracted out often to the lowest bidder and the Tories make no secret of the fact that they would love &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/jeremy-hunt-privatise-nhs-tories-privatising-private-insurance-market-replacement-direct-democracy-a6865306.html&quot;&gt;a health system like that of the US&lt;/a&gt;. It feels as if we are on a one way road to paying for our care through an insurance scheme that would see millions without care.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/health-cash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Money-in-a-savings-jar-marked-health&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is often stated that capitalism is the most efficient monetary system the world has ever seen. Creating wealth and jobs, bringing people out of poverty and creating healthy competition in order to see services streamlined and cost effective. Is this true? If only there was a crystal ball we could look into that would tell us what a privatised public service would look like… Oh yes, there is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we want to see what might happen if we did give incentive to profit in the healthcare sector we can look at several things. Of course we can look at the system in the USA where we will find huge numbers of those less fortunate unable to afford essential care and countless horror stories from those who can, but we can also look at the sectors and services in the UK that have already been privatised. The list is extensive, much longer than any other country in the world with &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4061613.stm&quot;&gt;42 major businesses employing almost 900,000 people privatised before 1990&lt;/a&gt; - so we’ll have to narrow it down a little. Let’s look at The rail network, telecommunications, manufacturing, prisons, the postal service and the care sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-rail-network&quot;&gt;The rail network&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A pole from the Guardian in 1999 suggested that 73% of all voters would support renationalising Railtrack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rail privatisation was scrutinised heavily when first proposed in the 1980’s under PM Margaret Thatcher with even Conservative MP’s and lords rigorously defending public ownership. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/982037.stm&quot;&gt;privatisation of the rail network began in 1993&lt;/a&gt; and was complete by 1997 under PM John Major. The service was split into multiple franchises and sold to a plethora of operators. Many of these operators are British companies with German state owned Deutsche Bahn now owning a considerable proportion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When first proposed, rail privatisation was supposed to deliver better and cheaper services. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.raildeliverygroup.com/files/Publications/2016-11_rdg_dataset.pdf&quot;&gt;A report by the Rail Delivery Group in December 2016&lt;/a&gt; stated that both freight and passenger journeys have increased significantly, safety satisfaction and number of services have all increased, delay’s are down but the impact of those delays are up, as is the average cost of rail fares with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.orr.gov.uk/__data/assets/pdf_file/0018/21591/rail-fares-index-january-2016.pdf&quot;&gt;an increase of 66.6% between 2004 and 2016 (over 72% for long distance journeys)&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://actionforrail.org/the-four-big-myths-of-uk-rail-privatisation/&quot;&gt;117%, or by 24% in real terms between 1995 and 2015&lt;/a&gt;. Better? Perhaps. Cheaper? Most definitely not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Profit has been a difficult item to research. From what ABB can gather, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/uknews/1574708/Rail-companies-profits-fares-and-salaries.html&quot;&gt;profits average around £50million with operator First Group pocketing £100million&lt;/a&gt;. Net support for the industry provided by the public in 2015-2016 was £4.8billion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we divide the £4.8billion by the 23 operators, that makes and average of £209 million per company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;telecommunications&quot;&gt;Telecommunications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally a part of the post office, &lt;a href=&quot;http://home.bt.com/news/bt-life/history-of-bt/a-short-history-of-telecommunications-in-the-uk-11363870786446&quot;&gt;British telecom became a Plc. in 1984&lt;/a&gt; as the first big British company to be privatised. Customer service records pre-1984 are difficult to come by so understanding value for money is difficult. However, we can see both current satisfaction levels compared to other landline providers and look at the share price over the last 30 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ofcom.org.uk/about-ofcom/latest/features-and-news/customer-service-satisfaction-levels-2014&quot;&gt;OFCOM, satisfaction with BT&lt;/a&gt; for landline services is fairly low at 61% compared to Sky’s 79% we can see that this really isn’t good enough. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/finance/personalfinance/investing/shares-and-stock-tips/9989430/Thatchers-legacy-how-has-privatisation-fared.html&quot;&gt;Share price, despite a brief spike during the 90’s dotcom boom has slowly dropped&lt;/a&gt; in real terms over the years. All of this suggests a serious flaw in the system and a lack of ability to compete in the private sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BT’s profits have also been dropping. An accounting scandal can be blamed partly for this although it is hard to believe a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.co.uk/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=5&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwizpN-dlP3UAhXIBcAKHb77DB0QFghBMAQ&amp;amp;url=https://www.theregister.co.uk/2017/01/27/bts_profits_plunge_37_following_italian_job/&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEFbgREg-bWqs2041KqbJO-EMVytQ&quot;&gt;37% drop&lt;/a&gt; can be put down to the one scandal. but one has to ask, with such incompetency, how can we trust such a private sector firm with arguably our most vital 21st century resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite their recent setbacks, in 2016 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.itv.com/news/2016-05-05/bt-pockets-3bn-profits-days-after-announcing-price-hikes-for-customers/&quot;&gt;BT announced £3 billion in profits shortly after raising the consumer cost by 15%&lt;/a&gt;. BT also receives public subsidies often for investment in new projects. The most recent of which was a £1.2 billion subsidy for its rural broadband upgrade investment. Both the Government and BT have defended the subsidy stating that the subsidies are “excellent value for money” ABB asks why, with profits of £3bn, and BT likely to be the main profiteers of such investment, the money has to come from the public purse. This however, is a question for another time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BT’s shares were originally intended to stay “at home” in the UK with shares split between employees and the public encouraged to buy way back in 1984 when the company was privatised. Now however BT’s majority shareholders are a small group of American investment corporations including Renaissance Technologies, Blackrock inc, Northern Trust Corp and Bank of America Corp. This means that the £3bn in profit sails across the pond to the shores of &lt;em&gt;cough&lt;/em&gt; our biggest ally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;manufacturing&quot;&gt;Manufacturing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may think I am stupid. I can barely believe it myself but yes… Once upon a time a large proportion of British Manufacturing was public. I myself only found this out during the research of this post. looking at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_privatizations&quot;&gt;list of privatisations&lt;/a&gt;  (Sorry, I know it’s Wikipedia) it is easy to see that a whole treasure trove of manufacturing industries have been sold off over the years. Some of these industries and businesses include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Steel Industry&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Coal Industry&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Automotive industry (for example Jaguar and Rolls Royce)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;British Sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;British Shipbuilding&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multiple aviation companies and airports&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Utility companies and infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;British Steel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look for yourself, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_privatizations&quot;&gt;the list seems endless.&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is impossible here, without an amazing mathematician, to work out the potential profits from all of these companies. ABB can only assume that they are massive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason we should look at these industries is this, quite frankly, many of them no longer exist and where they do, they often don’t operate in the UK or are even now, looking to shift operations overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;British Steel and British Coal for example have fallen victim to systematic break-up and sell off, or even just relentless closures. Manufacturing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ippr.org/files/images/media/files/publication/2011/05/manufacturering_in_uk_1285.pdf?noredirect=1&quot;&gt;between 1992 and 2002 fell from 21% to 17%&lt;/a&gt;.  This doesn’t seem like much but when you consider that output grew by 31% in that time this statistic is shocking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prisons&quot;&gt;Prisons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all prisons in the UK are private sector, however since 1992 14 of the UK’s prisons have been privatised through contracts much like the contracts in the rail system. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.politics.co.uk/reference/private-prisons&quot;&gt;Since 1990’s contracts have been issued for running of services&lt;/a&gt;, for most of the UK’s 88,000 prisoners. A vast majority of the projects have been given to G4S, a company known for its failure in the delivery of the 2012 Olympic security contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Problems in private prisons have been widely reported in recent months with G4S often at the centre of them. The sheer scale of atrocities and failures on the part of G4S is content suitable of a string of posts all by itself. Much like G4S prison staff however, but we are already overrun and must cut this down to size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kev, an inmate at Oakley ‘Super’ Prison commented when &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/society/2014/apr/29/tales-from-inside-oakwood-prison&quot;&gt;speaking to the Guardian&lt;/a&gt; “One day there were two new screws on together in charge of 60 men. They were asking me what to do to keep order. They hadn’t got a clue.” There are also reports of G4S Guards attacking children at Rainsbrook Prison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course there is no want on the part of private companies, to take on such contracts unless profit can be made. Companies such as G4S often aim for profit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/business/2017/02/18/end-private-prisons/&quot;&gt;margins of around 10%&lt;/a&gt; on contracts worth, as far as ABB can tell around £500 million each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-postal-service&quot;&gt;The postal service&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/finance/economics/11302648/Royal-Mails-privatisation-will-help-to-make-the-UK-economy-more-efficient.html&quot;&gt;The Post Office was part privatised in October 2013 for £3.30 per share&lt;/a&gt;, with the Government retaining 30%. It has done pretty well in shareholder value since. There was a scandal here when its first investors sold their shares quickly while effectively doubling their money despite making the government promises of long-term stable investment. But that is not the question here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the public no longer pay subsidies to Royal Mail or directly pay for it through taxation, stamp prices have risen from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stampmagazine.co.uk/news/article/2013-royal-mail-stamp-prices/14716&quot;&gt;60p and 50p&lt;/a&gt; in 2013 to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.royalmail.com/sites/default/files/Royal-Mail-Franking-Wallchart-March-17.pdf&quot;&gt;65p and 56p&lt;/a&gt; in 2017, much less than the price hikes experienced through other privatisations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customer and employee satisfaction don’t seem to have been affected and efficiency of service is as it always has been. There isn’t much change from the public’s perspective and so we can probably call this a privatisation success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employees may disagree however as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thetimes.co.uk/article/strike-action-in-the-post-over-a-second-class-royal-mail-pension-dvlsr2x5s&quot;&gt;major pensions scandal&lt;/a&gt; has ensued with strike action narrowly averted by Monday’s new pensions deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only time will tell if we can truly call the Royal Mail privatisation a success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-care-sector&quot;&gt;The care sector&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was one of the first privatisations I actually remember. While walking past a council run care home with a friend of mine who happened to work inside, I was told that there were plans to close the home, sell the care contracts to private organisations and replace the majority of the service with “home care”. I was young and naïve and I have to say, I didn’t believe it. I told her “The public won’t let it happen. They will stand up and fight because many can’t afford their own care there will be someone out there who knows how to put up a fight”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we are, in 2017 and council run care homes are a thing of the past. This is a great example of how creeping privatisation works. Over the years contracts have been put out to tender, again using the rail network model until we have reached a situation whereby &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/careers/2016/jun/21/privatisation-social-care-workforce-careers&quot;&gt;three in four of the UK’s care homes are run for profit&lt;/a&gt;. Homes have been sold, demolished or replaced with a private sector equivalent all on the ‘hush-hush’. The public didn’t know what was happening and so they could not organise an effective response. Those who did know were often disbelieved and ignored. Something for which I will forever feel personally guilty for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.lse.ac.uk/politicsandpolicy/why-social-care-privatisation-is-unsuccessful/&quot;&gt;creeping privatisation of the care sector has happened over the past 30 years&lt;/a&gt; or so and with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/populationandmigration/populationestimates/articles/overviewoftheukpopulation/mar2017&quot;&gt;population ageing&lt;/a&gt; and with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.lse.ac.uk/politicsandpolicy/why-social-care-privatisation-is-unsuccessful/&quot;&gt;current financial size of £22billion&lt;/a&gt;, the sector is extremely attractive for investors and men (and women) in suits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tragedy is however, that without a low cost, well regulated public service for care providing secure work for the profession, a combination of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/careers/2016/jun/21/privatisation-social-care-workforce-careers&quot;&gt;zero hour contracts&lt;/a&gt; and minimum wage often attract the lowest of skilled workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The care sector it has consistently failed, but it doesn’t stop here. The private care sector is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kingsfund.org.uk/press/press-releases/social-care-budget-cuts-damaging-nhs-latest-quarterly-monitoring-report-finds&quot;&gt;Damaging the NHS&lt;/a&gt; with delayed hospital discharges while failing to reduce emergency admissions. The sector is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kingsfund.org.uk/projects/new-gov/three-priorities-new-government&quot;&gt;under funded&lt;/a&gt;; it is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-31001151&quot;&gt;financially crippling&lt;/a&gt; for users who often must sell their homes to pay for care. Care workers are overworked and underpaid with no job security, there are serious &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/12/05/care-home-fees-soar-one-quarter-quality-plummets-report-finds/&quot;&gt;concerns about the quality of care&lt;/a&gt; and all the while providers say the industry is on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/e6c08ebe-0d47-11e7-a88c-50ba212dce4d?mhq5j=e1&quot;&gt;verge of collapse&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;back-to-the-nhs&quot;&gt;Back to the NHS…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fullfact.org/health/how-much-more-nhs-spending-private-providers/&quot;&gt;10% of NHS services are already contracted to private organisations&lt;/a&gt;, this is a trend that is rising steadily. Private services often provide a cleaner, better and more optimised service and when I used one for an ultrasound scan during the appointment, I was impressed. This however did not last for long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I received my scan I went about my business. After not hearing about any results for a while (for what was quite a sizeable scary lump on my neck) I found myself sat in front of an angry GP. I had booked an appointment to see if the results had come through only to find myself berated for not turning up to the scan. I had turned up. It eventually became clear that the scan had been ‘lost’, not seen for weeks and when it did eventually show up, it was found in my GP’s private inbox and not in the system it should have been. A serious breach of data protection to say the least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only this but my GP was supposed to receive a letter after the scan, detailing the results that she could then forward to me. This didn’t happen and instead, in an attempt to cover their tracks a letter was sent claiming I had not turned up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not alone in these incidents. Recently over &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.essexlive.news/over-9-000-nhs-health-records-lost-by-private-company-in-essex-suffolk-and-norfolk/story-29873676-detail/story.html&quot;&gt;9,000 records were lost by private healthcare companies in Essex&lt;/a&gt; and while speaking to a healthcare professional who wishes to remain anonymous, ABB has been told of the same private clinic mislaying or just not forwarding many medical records with NHS doctors and nurses often having to chase up results manually. This often wastes time and money that could be spent healing people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should mention however that the care I received during my problem was ultimately second to none and I am eternally grateful to the great staff who helped me out immensely. I am forever indebted to our beautiful, public NHS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;should-we-allow-the-creeping-privatisation-of-the-nhs&quot;&gt;Should we allow the creeping privatisation of the NHS?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the above evidence we can see that when a service is privatised, often profit is put before service. Hardly a privatisation seems to have been a success story in the past with the possible exception of Royal Mail, which has not been in private hands long enough for us to understand. It is difficult to see how a private NHS would work for the benefit of the people it serves while still striving to make a profit. Surely a better answer would be to re-think national insurance in such away that it covers the NHS bill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-can-be-done&quot;&gt;What can be done?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, as we saw with the care sector this is going to be a difficult fight. If you agree with ABB that it is a fight worth taking up there are some simple actions you can take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;join-a-union&quot;&gt;Join a Union&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you work in the NHS a great way to fight is by joining the union &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unison.org.uk/at-work/health-care/key-issues/fighting-cuts-and-privatisation-in-the-nhs/&quot;&gt;UNISON&lt;/a&gt;. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unison.org.uk/at-work/health-care/key-issues/fighting-cuts-and-privatisation-in-the-nhs/&quot;&gt;join UNSION&lt;/a&gt; if you work in any public service and help to add your voice to those already fighting for our NHS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;keep-up-to-date&quot;&gt;Keep up to date&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://keepournhspublic.com/&quot;&gt;Keep our nhs public&lt;/a&gt; is a great site with all the most up-to-date information regarding NHS privatisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;join-the-labour-party&quot;&gt;Join the Labour Party&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Labour Party under Jeremy Corbyn is currently the best placed party to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.labour.org.uk/blog/entry/end-nhs-privatisation&quot;&gt;fend off the attacks on our NHS&lt;/a&gt;. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://join.labour.org.uk/&quot;&gt;join The Labour Party&lt;/a&gt; for as little as £2 a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;read-all-about-it&quot;&gt;Read all about it&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/0850366275/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1634&amp;amp;creative=6738&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0850366275&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=mrbrompton-21&amp;amp;linkId=13aef07626077e7cef1a8b21727781f4&quot;&gt;NHS for Sale: Myths, Lies and Deception&lt;/a&gt; looks at the issue in depth. Read up and equip yourself with the best weapon in this fight… information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you thought this post was helpful you can support ABB in a number of ways. Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anotherblogblog.co.uk/support.html&quot;&gt;ABB support page&lt;/a&gt;, give us a like and follow us for everything you need to fight the good fight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;fb-like&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ABB.Mr.Brompton&quot; data-layout=&quot;button_count&quot; data-action=&quot;like&quot; data-size=&quot;large&quot; data-show-faces=&quot;false&quot; data-share=&quot;false&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fb-follow&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ABB.Mr.Brompton&quot; data-layout=&quot;button_count&quot; data-size=&quot;large&quot; data-show-faces=&quot;false&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Social Media, Gift or Curse?</title>
    <link href="http://www.anotherblogblog.co.uk /big-issues/life/2017/07/04/social-media/"/>
    <updated>2017-07-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.anotherblogblog.co.uk/big-issues/life/2017/07/04/social-media</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;iframe id=&quot;ad&quot; style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-eu.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;amp;OneJS=1&amp;amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;amp;MarketPlace=GB&amp;amp;source=ac&amp;amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;amp;tracking_id=mrbrompton-21&amp;amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;amp;region=GB&amp;amp;placement=B01KXDSJA6&amp;amp;asins=B01KXDSJA6&amp;amp;linkId=c49eae69460eff5d6978d5729da068b2&amp;amp;show_border=false&amp;amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true&amp;amp;price_color=333333&amp;amp;title_color=ff6600&amp;amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;social-media-gift-or-curse&quot;&gt;Social Media: Gift or Curse?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;drayzera&quot;&gt;DrayZera&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fb-like&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ABB.Mr.Brompton&quot; data-layout=&quot;button_count&quot; data-action=&quot;like&quot; data-size=&quot;large&quot; data-show-faces=&quot;false&quot; data-share=&quot;false&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fb-follow&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ABB.Mr.Brompton&quot; data-layout=&quot;button_count&quot; data-size=&quot;large&quot; data-show-faces=&quot;false&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People are depressed even more,
But… Do you know the social score?
Well, we can’t necessarily put a finger on it,
Yet the low lit screens flickers and suffocates us… Oh social media… Is killing us all!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/facebook-addict.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pills in a facebook packet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome ONE AND ALL to my debut article on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anotherblogblog.co.uk&quot;&gt;Another Blog Blog&lt;/a&gt;! My name is DrayZera and while I chomp on my sausage rolls en route from Liverpool Lime Street to Shoreham-On-Sea near Brighton, I’d like to login to my thoughts in regards to social media (see what I did here) and that it’s killing us all! Here is why…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a person born in the earliest of 90s, I grew up away from the computer world and by the time I hit my teens I recall using a floppy-disk to save my work from Microsoft Power-point!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OH HOW THE WORLD HAS CHANGED!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some stats:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;quot&quot;&gt;&quot;84% of all UK adults use social media... YouTube and Facebook are by far the most popular platforms among UK adults online (respectively 85% and 78%)&quot;&lt;span class=&quot;ref&quot;&gt;Stats from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://weareflint.co.uk/press-release-uk-social-media-demographics-2016/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;We Are Flint Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to social media - hashtags, selfies, filters and memes all are prevalent and are a part of society’s idiolect lingo! Now, while new language is always a fresh welcome to the ever-bulging Oxford Dictionary, it’s important to know the ABSOLUTE SPEED this is happening… Within the last 5-10 years!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;quot&quot;&gt;&quot;In March 2007, less than a year after opening to the public, the social network had 30 million users.&quot; &lt;span class=&quot;ref&quot;&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;betanews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And with time flying… So does the frazzle effect it inflicts upon the human mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has caused infection and poison upon the innocent in that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/12161461/Facebook-addiction-activates-same-part-of-the-brain-as-cocaine.html&quot;&gt;your mind has to CONTINUE to look at Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, BURROW YOUR MIND unto those absolute terrible videos from Buzzers and so on! We are hooked and we are addicted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, DISCLAIMER, I’m not saying that social media in itself is bad at all! Quite the contrary! The tools that social media has in abundance have allowed yours truly to spread his performer name worldwide and has assisted my lifestyle muchly! However, the way we are applying social media is killing us without remorse… So here’s the cold hard discourse I’d like to share:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking behind a screen is easier than talking in front of one another - Bullying on the Internet is vile especially when you see comments such as “kys” (an acronym for Kill Yourself) and so on! Leads to depression, anxiety and with lots of pain mentally, physically and emotionally. Not many likes to confront face to face…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spending too much time in the electronic world compared to the REAL World - You get games such as “World Of Warcraft” “Second Life” and Twich Livestreaming which incorporates a heavy Social Media aspect and therefore neglecting the beautiful nature of skylines, beaches and roller coasters! Sleep deprivation and the feeling of “Wasting your life away” is there! Now, if you’re a pro gamer and making money then that’s cool! However, the vast majority of us don’t and while money isn’t everything… Spending hours not investing in yourself in reality isn’t right!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;are-social-skills-deminishing&quot;&gt;Are social skills deminishing?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have realised in my months of travelling far and wide that &lt;a href=&quot;http://newsroom.ucla.edu/releases/in-our-digital-world-are-young-people-losing-the-ability-to-read-emotions&quot;&gt;people’s social skills have deminished&lt;/a&gt; greatly in comparison to the older generation! By not practicing social skills person to person has caused us to become more of a hermit and therefore has become quite the factor in developing phobias with people as a consequence!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SO with all that said… What’s the solution?
Simple.
Social Media less, go out more!
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/DrayZera/&quot;&gt;DrayZera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need to get away from social media? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B01KXDSJA6/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1634&amp;amp;creative=6738&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B01KXDSJA6&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=mrbrompton-21&amp;amp;linkId=96b175b875981ee4f808a09715a9aec5&quot;&gt;Hooked: Overcoming Social Media Addiction&lt;/a&gt; is a great book that tackles this issue. Support ABB and hold the real thing in your hands… Theres nothing like a proper book!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;fb-like&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ABB.Mr.Brompton&quot; data-layout=&quot;button_count&quot; data-action=&quot;like&quot; data-size=&quot;large&quot; data-show-faces=&quot;false&quot; data-share=&quot;false&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fb-follow&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ABB.Mr.Brompton&quot; data-layout=&quot;button_count&quot; data-size=&quot;large&quot; data-show-faces=&quot;false&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Jeremy Corbyn</title>
    <link href="http://www.anotherblogblog.co.uk /politics/ge2017/2017/06/06/Corbyn-Mugwump/"/>
    <updated>2017-06-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.anotherblogblog.co.uk/politics/ge2017/2017/06/06/Corbyn-Mugwump</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;iframe id=&quot;ad&quot; style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-eu.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;amp;OneJS=1&amp;amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;amp;MarketPlace=GB&amp;amp;source=ac&amp;amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;amp;tracking_id=mrbrompton-21&amp;amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;amp;region=GB&amp;amp;placement=B072C293XW&amp;amp;asins=B072C293XW&amp;amp;linkId=98553a0d938e56d079000383bea17ca7&amp;amp;show_border=false&amp;amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true&amp;amp;price_color=333333&amp;amp;title_color=0066c0&amp;amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;mr-corbyn-irish-bombing-terrorist-sympathising-mugwump&quot;&gt;Mr. Corbyn: Irish Bombing, Terrorist Sympathising Mugwump.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mr-brompton&quot;&gt;Mr. Brompton&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;fb-like&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ABB.Mr.Brompton&quot; data-layout=&quot;button_count&quot; data-action=&quot;like&quot; data-size=&quot;large&quot; data-show-faces=&quot;false&quot; data-share=&quot;false&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fb-follow&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ABB.Mr.Brompton&quot; data-layout=&quot;button_count&quot; data-size=&quot;large&quot; data-show-faces=&quot;false&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jeremy Corbyn… Well well, what can I say? I used to think you were a decent bloke but recently I must say I may have changed my mind. It’s like someone has washed away all my positive thoughts about a leader who is kind, compassionate, strong enough to withstand a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-36647458&quot;&gt;coup of 172 MP’s&lt;/a&gt; intent on destroying any hopes the Labour party had of being a left-wing representative party. If only there was a word to describe this cleansing of thought…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/Terror-loving-mugwump.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jeremy-Corbyn-IRA-Terrorist&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;proper-mugwump&quot;&gt;Proper Mugwump&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here you are, lording your victory over us doing things like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-36647458&quot;&gt;riding the bus&lt;/a&gt;. I mean, what sort of future PM really acts like the people he is hoping to lead? Because you are hoping to lead aren’t you? I mean, everyone says you don’t want to be the leader - that it was just &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-341842650&quot;&gt;your turn to stand&lt;/a&gt;. I certainly don’t believe that a reluctant leader, who sees himself as part of the team in anyway can be good at the task. It’s not as if there are any &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/1848258755/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1634&amp;amp;creative=6738&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1848258755&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=mrbrompton-21&amp;amp;linkId=50327d367c9c66a7d8ccd13671feaf9f&quot;&gt;books on the issue&lt;/a&gt;, or even people at the forefront of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.skillpath.co.uk/on-site-blog/post.cfm/reluctant-leader&quot;&gt;leadership field of expertise suggesting reluctant leaders are a good idea&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this is besides the point when I really think about it. How can I, in good conscience, vote for a man who has &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/politics/Jeremy_Corbyn/11924431/Revealed-Jeremy-Corbyn-and-John-McDonnells-close-IRA-links.html&quot;&gt;stood next to another man from the IRA&lt;/a&gt;. Never mind the fact that your actions helped work towards the lasting peace that we now all enjoy or that you have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rt.com/uk/311827-corbyn-british-army-ira/&quot;&gt;repeatedly condemned the actions&lt;/a&gt; on BOTH sides of that terrible war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes Jeremy, now we all know you can’t hide behind your back-bench anymore. Take your place in the firing line so that we can all take pot-shots at you like those terrorists with which you symapathise take shots at us. Don’t get me wrong, it wasn’t me, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2015/dec/01/cameron-accuses-corbyn-of-being-terrorist-sympathiser&quot;&gt;David Cameron called you, Mr. Corbyn the terrorist sympathiser&lt;/a&gt; and of course &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mirror.co.uk/news/uk-news/10-big-policy-promises-broken-6965585&quot;&gt;David Cameron would never lie to us&lt;/a&gt;. By my reckoning if those pesky terrorists hate pork, &lt;a href=&quot;http://time.com/4043311/david-cameron-pig-gate-scandal/&quot;&gt;anyone who likes bacon so much&lt;/a&gt; must be honest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there is my FAVOURITE MP Mr. BJ. Now, I don’t know any &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theyworkforyou.com/mp/10999/boris_johnson/uxbridge_and_south_ruislip/votes&quot;&gt;decisions Boris has made&lt;/a&gt; but I do know that he makes me laugh. He called you a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mugwumps&quot;&gt;mugwump&lt;/a&gt; A word I have never heard of but that apparently does have a definition*. If he calls you a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mugwumps&quot;&gt;mugwump&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mugwumps&quot;&gt;mugwump&lt;/a&gt; you must be&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;quot&quot;&gt;&quot;a person who remains aloof or independent, especially from party politics. It originates from North American politics and dates back to 1832&quot;&lt;span class=&quot;ref&quot;&gt;-Google. Congratulations BJ. I like something you said.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So who do you think you are kidding Mr. Corbyn? When you think the Tories are done? Just because you have consistently out-performed Therasa May, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.labour.org.uk/page/-/Images/manifesto-2017/Funding%20Britain%27s%20Future.PDF&quot;&gt;properly costed your manifesto&lt;/a&gt; and are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/general-election-latest-labour-party-conservative-party-poll-survation-good-morning-britain-a7762371.html&quot;&gt;closing the gap in the polls&lt;/a&gt; it doesn’t mean you get my vote. Nah, I think I’ll give it to that guy who wants to legalise weed… What was his name again?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;back-to-reality&quot;&gt;Back to reality&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself using the arguments above please take a second to question your sources. Find something that you truly disagree with, or better still - something you agree with that can be backed up. You have a world of information at your fingertips. You can question us on economics, the welfare state, Tax Avoidance, education or just policies in general. Please do, I could use the mental exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must confess… The bait was there, I had to take it. I’ve heard statements like those above repeated so often and heard so little considered and thoughtful response I felt the opportunity could not be missed. I’m sorry, I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next post will return to the Labour Manifesto. With time running short I will be overviewing the manifesto costings and hopefully allowing me a little time to focus on other issues ‘JC and the Big Bad BREXIT Monster’ is a working title. If you like it let me know, comment below or feel free to click ‘contact’ at the bottom of the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading. I don’t use Google Analytics. This means I don’t leave cookies on your computer. It also means that I am blind. Please, if you liked this let me know by giving me a click up top. If you find this useful please share it so others can share in the usefulness. Think you’ve missed one? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anotherblogblog.co.uk/pages/blog&quot;&gt;All my posts can be found in my blogs section&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;fb-like&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ABB.Mr.Brompton&quot; data-layout=&quot;button_count&quot; data-action=&quot;like&quot; data-size=&quot;large&quot; data-show-faces=&quot;false&quot; data-share=&quot;false&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fb-follow&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ABB.Mr.Brompton&quot; data-layout=&quot;button_count&quot; data-size=&quot;large&quot; data-show-faces=&quot;false&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Grenfell</title>
    <link href="http://www.anotherblogblog.co.uk /politics/2017/05/17/grenfell/"/>
    <updated>2017-05-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.anotherblogblog.co.uk/politics/2017/05/17/grenfell</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;iframe id=&quot;ad&quot; style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-eu.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;amp;OneJS=1&amp;amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;amp;MarketPlace=GB&amp;amp;source=ac&amp;amp;ref=tf_til&amp;amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;amp;tracking_id=mrbrompton-21&amp;amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;amp;region=GB&amp;amp;placement=B00M1Q70K4&amp;amp;asins=B00M1Q70K4&amp;amp;linkId=3a3be906691c7f6c790016ab9b14086b&amp;amp;show_border=false&amp;amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true&amp;amp;price_color=333333&amp;amp;title_color=ff6600&amp;amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;grenfell-tower-fire-what-are-we-missing&quot;&gt;Grenfell Tower Fire: What are we missing?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;by-mr-brompton&quot;&gt;By Mr. Brompton&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;fb-like&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ABB.Mr.Brompton&quot; data-layout=&quot;button_count&quot; data-action=&quot;like&quot; data-size=&quot;large&quot; data-show-faces=&quot;false&quot; data-share=&quot;false&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fb-follow&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ABB.Mr.Brompton&quot; data-layout=&quot;button_count&quot; data-size=&quot;large&quot; data-show-faces=&quot;false&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fb-like&quot; data-href=&quot;http://www.anotherblogblog.co.uk/Blog/GE2017/grenfell-tower-fire.html&quot; data-layout=&quot;button_count&quot; data-action=&quot;like&quot; data-size=&quot;large&quot; data-show-faces=&quot;true&quot; data-share=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Like This post&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last week we saw a tragedy the like of which is unthinkable and unseen here in the UK, the tragic deaths of many men, women and children trapped inside a towering inferno. Our hearts go out to all of those who lost their lives, who must live with horrific injuries and who will never see their loved ones again and of course, to those who we may never identify. Another Blog Blog also wish to thank the Community, the emergency services and the public who have come together in an amazing show of humanity. At first this post was intending look into the fire in great detail but after conducting research some disturbing information has come to light. Information I feel the need to share across the country.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/Grenfell_Tower_fire_morning.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jeremy-Corbyn-IRA-Terrorist&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-issue&quot;&gt;The Issue&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should begin at the start of the trail, looking at the possibility that the fire was preventable. With reports focusing on the poor safety standards and external cladding of the building, Another Blog Blog fear that something big is being missed. These measures, although important to minimise the risk to life when such incidents occur do not in themselves stop these horrible tragedies. There is no doubt a case to hear of corporate manslaughter through negligence by the Housing Management Organisation and the Council but the question here is ‘Was this preventable’. To understand this, we must look at the ‘cause’ of the fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many reports on the night suggested that the fire may have started with a faulty fridge. Behailu Kebede, a taxi driver who lived on the fourth floor admitted he thought this would be a small fire and was told by emergency services it could be kept under control. Sadly, we know this was not the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should remember that the fire experts have not yet concluded their investigation into the cause of the fire however Mr. Behailu’s testimony corroborates with other tenant’s reports. It also matches with what &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-1210334/Alert-new-wave-exploding-fridges-caused-environmentally-friendly-coolant.html#ixzz4kNl3PwK4&quot;&gt;Graeme Fox, an air-conditioning and refrigeration contractor told The Mail back in 2009&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;quot&quot;&gt;&quot;During the day when the fridge door is frequently opened there isn't a problem. 'But at night, when everyone is sleeping and the door remains shut, this leaked highly flammable gas can build up in the fridge cabinet&quot;
&lt;span class=&quot;ref&quot;&gt;- Graeme Fox&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Domestic fridge explosions seem to be on the increase. Another Blog Blog has found numerous reports that seem to start around 2010 of refrigerators exploding in this manner and so we looked into it further. Isobutane seems to be the cause here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;quot&quot;&gt;&quot;Similar explosions with similar consequences have also occurred in homes across Europe and the Far East where domestic fridges now use flammable isobutane as the refrigerant. In these incidents, explosions have occurred if, due to a fault in the refrigerator, the flammable refrigerant has been able to leak into the refrigerator compartment.&quot;&lt;span class=&quot;ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coolingpost.com/world-news/lab-explosion-due-to-domestic-fridge/&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;- Coolpost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reports surfaced in 2009 of refrigerators with the compound isobutane exploding when leaked into the refrigeration compartment. Reports seem to have been largely ignored by the press, government and public. Jane Gartshore, president of the Institute of Refrigeration speaking to the telegraph stated that this is “theoretically possible” but “There are hundreds of millions of these fridges and these incidents are very rare.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rarity may be the case, but as seen in an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.birminghammail.co.uk/news/midlands-news/investigation-what-caused-massive-explosion-11149998&quot;&gt;explosion that destroyed a house in Birmingham&lt;/a&gt; surely the potential dangers outweigh the rarity. It is rare that an aeroplane crashes and kills its passengers, but safety measures still have to be in place to prevent these horrific disasters. Why is it not the same for appliance manufacturers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is difficult to find statistics in the UK, perhaps a freedom of information request to HMRC or the companies in question could reveal the information but this will take time. In the meantime there are two places we can look for information&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.london-fire.gov.uk/news/LatestNewsReleases_gaping-hole-in-fridge-freezer-safety.asp#.WUbbN1TyvIU&quot;&gt;LFB produced a report&lt;/a&gt; in Feb this year stating that there has been at least one fire per day in the capital alone since 2011 with eight deaths and aproximately 120 injuries. That number could be about to increase significantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should note that the company names most often surfacing in the reports of exploding fridges are Indecit, Hotpoint, Creda, Beko and Samsung.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we have seen with the recent Whirlpool, Indecit, Hotpoint and Creda tumble drier fires, companies with vested interest in the story not ‘getting out’ often show a serious lack of willingness to act. This is hardly a suprise but it would seem prudent that any inquest or inquiry into the matter should question if not prosecute company directors if it can be shown that a similar lack of response has infact caused the deaths of hundreds of people with whole families including children condemned to a tragic, painful and needless death. With over 300 million fridges worldwide using this technology reported in 2009 this could be a classic example of coorperate manslaughter through negligenance on a scale not precidented here in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a chance however, for these companies to put this right and YOU CAN HELP. UK manufacturers are about to produce a report for the International Electrotechnical Commission (IEC), the body that sets the global standards for manufacturing fridges and freezers on safety standards for future appliances. The LFB are campaiging for stronger safegaurds to be in place that include the use of fireproof material on the back of every refridgerator and could mean the difference between fridge A and fridge B in the video below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube&quot; width=&quot;854&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Pvko16hqJ7g&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This video shows how a fireproof backing can buy the vital time needed for the fire service to respond. The first fridge burns out of control within 20 seconds yet the fridge with the fireproof backing just smoulders for over 20 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-help&quot;&gt;How to help&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The LFB are our heroes. They put their lives on the line daily to defend our lives in the front line and lead campaigns for change in the industry. You can &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.london-fire.gov.uk/total-recalls-white-goods-campaign.asp&quot;&gt;support the LFB’s total recall campaign&lt;/a&gt; which aims to create a single register of known faulty appliances reducing the number of needless deaths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.parliament.uk/get-involved/contact-your-mp/&quot;&gt;contact your MP&lt;/a&gt;, asking them to raise the concerns of the LFB in parliament, back any calls to make appliances safer and to apply pressure to British manufacturers to amend their proposals in line with the LFB’s advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find information on preventing this type of fire from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ukfiretraining.com/news/fridge-freezer-fires.html&quot;&gt;UKFireTraining.com&lt;/a&gt;. Remember to fit and check a smoke alarm as seen in the affiliate link to the right. It could be the difference between life and death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This information could help save lives. It could help to bring some meaning to the deaths of those so tragically lost. Share it far and wide – Not for ABB but for those children who never had a chance and whose last breathes where the most painful imaginable. Thank you for reading.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>